### Erik Hartman

Lund, Sweden

📕+46 727413988 | 🗷 erik.hartman@hotmail.com | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200 | 200

### Personal Profile

I hold an MSc in biomedical engineering, and have a passion for research and science. In my studies, I specialized in data-science and computational biology, and published peer-reviewed articles parallel to studying at a faster pace than expected. My research mainly revolves around creating and utilizing computational methods for the analysis of omics data. Lately, I've dove deeply into machine learning algorithms and their application in understanding complex diseases.

I'm currently working as a research engineer, in the process of starting my PhD.

### Education \_\_

LTH, Lund University

Lund, Sweden

MSc with a focus on Computational Biology

Sept 2021 - Oct 2022

- Finished the 5 year program in 4 years, as I was routinely studying at a faster pace than expected.
- Relevant courses: advanced algorithms, modelling of biological systems, stochastic systems, Monte Carlo simulations, image analysis (& medical image analysis).

LTH, Lund University

Lund, Sweden

BSc in Biomedical Engineering

Sept 2018 - June 2021

- Courses: The courses in my bachelors range from calculus, thermodynamics and programming to cell biology, human physiology and designtheory.
- Parallel to my studies at LTH, I also joined the medical faculty to study biomedicine for a year.

### Academic Awards

2021	Best thesis, Clinical innovation (Klinnovation)	Lund, Sweden
2019	Gold medal, interntational Genetically Engineered Machine (iGEM)	Boston, USA
2018	<b>3rd place</b> , Intel ISEF, category of translational medicine	Pittsburgh, USA
2018	1st place, National Science Comptetion for Young Scientists (Unga Forskare)	Stockholm, Sweden
2018	<b>High school awards</b> , Highest achiever in biology, best high school scientific project, and high grades.	Lund, Sweden
2015	<b>Lower education awards,</b> Highest achiever in chemistry and pshychology, and awarded for extraordinary	Cinannoro
	general accomplishments.	Singapore

#### **Publications**

First authored articles are shown below. For a full list of references, please see my personal website: https://erikhartman.github.io/.

## Community-based peptidomic clustering reveals pathogen-specific proteolytic signatures in wounds

In review

**Hartman E.,** Forsberg F., Kjellström S., Petrlova J., Luo C., Scott A., Puthia M., Malmström J., Schmidtchen A.

2023

• DOI: https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.12.28.573527

## Interpreting biologically informed neural networks for enhanced biomarker discovery and pathway analysis

Nature Communications

**Hartman E.,** Scott A., Malmström L., Malmström J.

2023

• DOI: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-023-41146-4

# Bioinformatic Analysis of the Wound Peptidome Reveals Potential Biomarkers and Antimicrobial Peptides

Frontiers in Immunology

Hartman E., Wallblom K., Kjellström S., Schmidtchen A.

202.

• DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2020.620707

Peptimetric: Quantifying and Visualizing Differences in Peptidomic Data

Frontiers in Bioinformatics

Hartman E., Mahdavi S., Kjellström S., Schmidtchen A.

2021

• DOI: https://doi.org/10.3389/fbinf.2021.722466

JANUARY 15, 2024 1

### **Relevant Work Experience**

#### **Medical faculty, Lund University**

Lund, Sweden

Researcher 2020 - Present

• I've been conducting research in different groups at the department of infection medicine at Lund University. After finishing my MSc I was hired as a lab engineer at the infection medicine proteomics lab.

• Skillset: programming (various languages), mass spectrometry, omics, machine learning, graph theory, game theory, statistics, data visualiza-

**Olucore** Lund, Sweden

Machine learning developer

Feb 2023 - July 2023

Qlucore develops software for the analysis of omics data. I've joined the team to implement machine learning algorithms into the software.

• Skillset: Python, C++, machine learning, git.

**Dianovator** Malmö, Sweden

Bioinformatic consultant

Apr 2022 - June 2022

· Dianovator develops algorithms for advanced insulin pumps. I helped them implement a summary report system for their software.

• **Skillset:** Python, MySQL, general data analysis and visualization.

LTH & elsewhere Lund, Sweden

Tutor 2019 - 2022

• Throughout my studies I've worked as a tutor - private as well as at LTH as a lecturer. My private tutoring was mainly in mathematics at both a high-school and university level. At LTH I lectured, as well as created and supervised computer exercises in the course Data-driven Health (BMEN35).

### Other Interests\_

I compete in powerlifting at an international level and am the head of the local powerlifting organization, consisting of >160 Powerlifting

members. Beyond training for hours most days, this entails various administrative tasks making sure the organization runs

smoothly as well as arranging training camps and competitions.

I created an organization with the aim to investigate the ethical dilemmas related to research in the fields of gene-editing and **Philosophy** synthetic biology. The organization was very active 2019-2021, and had >30 members from around the globe. Our Facebook-page

is still up: https://www.facebook.com/synthethicsinitiative

The Organization for Young Scientists is a national Swedish organization hosting science competitions and seminars, as well as

**Young Scientists** acting as an umbrella-organization for student organizations and clubs. Beyond competing, I was engaged in the organization by

arranging competitions, being a board-member, and most recently as a judge at the national science competition.

JANUARY 15, 2024